I have to say,
Lijia Town's streets are quite lively.
I'll take a newspaper.
Bro Xun, pay him.
Lijia Gold Shop really got robbed. Stop!
Stop right there!
Hand it over!
Take him away.
Yes, Inspector.
Don't move!
A female inspector?
Why is it you guys again?
See for yourself.
Lijia Gold Shop.
The Five Ghosts Carrying Wealth?
Lijia Gold Shop was robbed last night.
Don't tell me you didn't know.
Don't even mention it.
That night watchman last night
died before finishing his sentence.
The archer also got away.
In just one night,
how did Lijia Gold Shop get robbed?
The King of Hell's Wedding
was a smokescreen to begin with.
Its real target
was the Lijia Gold Shop.
How did you find more clues?
Let's hear it.
Wait.
Inspector Mu!
Something terrible happened!
Let's go, let's go!
The door has a special Linglong Lock.
The key isn't missing.
These windows
were locked from the inside.
Every two hours at night,
someone patrols the area.
But despite all the precautions,
we can guard against humans,
but we can't guard against ghosts!
The Five Ghosts Carrying Wealth
carried away all the gold
from the shop!
Nonsense!
It was clearly a robbery by thieves.
Five Ghosts Carrying Wealth? Nonsense!
Inspector,
it was the Five Ghosts Carrying Wealth!
When I was patrolling last night,
I saw it with my own eyes.
It wasn't until dawn
that I finally woke up,
only to find the gold in the shop
had already been
cleared out by the Five Ghosts.
What's going on?
Was it really the Five Ghosts?
These flimsy paper-mache things...
You call these the Five Ghosts?
They can carry wealth?
It's absolutely true!
Master,
this place is way too creepy.
Let's get out of here.
Five Ghosts Carrying Wealth...
This yellow powder on their faces is
Linglong Lock.
You saw the Five Ghosts Carrying Wealth?
What did your Five-Sense Deduction find?
What's this?
Datura powder.
Datura powder?
Exactly.
Does this have anything to do
with the Five Ghosts Carrying Wealth?
The servant on patrol last night
saw someone pushing a cart.
It held five paper figures.
The paper figures
were covered in this Datura powder.
The servant inhaled it and hallucinated.
Fooled by Five Ghosts Carrying Wealth,
he saw thieves disguised as Five Ghosts.
And these five paper figures
are nothing but
a trick by the thieves to deceive people.
I knew it.
There are no ghosts.
It must have been the thieves.
So the Five Ghosts were a hallucination.
But the doors and windows were locked.
The lock on the gold shop
is an anti-theft Linglong Lock.
The so-called Linglong Lock
is nothing more than an ordinary lock.
Swindlers renamed it to raise the price,
just to scam money from wealthy families.
Then after the thieves pried open the gold shop,
what happened next?
Follow me.
Judging from the wheel tracks,
they must have pushed three carts
to transport the gold away.
Where did they take it?
To the east of Lijia Town are mountains.
Wooden wheels on mountain roads
would be very bumpy
and slow to push.
I'm absolutely certain
that they headed west.
To the Lijia River Dock.
They went by water.
Lijia River Dock.
Alright, I'll go now.
Thank you.
Look for the boat with the deepest draft.
Got it.
So the story goes,
My master uses his Five-Sense Deduction
Just recently,
he walked around the Lijia Gold Shop,
and perfectly reconstructed
the truth of the Lijia Gold Shop theft.
It turns out
the night watchman
was a scout for the gang of thieves.
They poisoned wealthy families' brides,
then posed as the King of Hell
to steal the brides' corpses.
They even spread rumors
about the King of Hell's Wedding
to distract the police.
In reality,
what they truly wanted to steal
was the richest man Benefactor Li's shop.
But all these criminal tricks
my master saw right through them!
Bravo!
Sir.
I'm Mengzhu, heiress to Lijia Gold Shop.
May I ask, sir,
how do you know about our shop's theft?
Would you honor us with a visit?
My apprentice and I are both hungry.
We need to go eat.
Come eat at my house.
I'll tell our chef
to cook an Imperial Feast for you.
Thank you for your kindness, Miss,
but I am just a commoner.
It's inappropriate for me to visit.
Farewell.
Let's go.
Miss.
What a clueless bookworm.
Let's ignore him.
Let's take a stroll at the Temple Fair.
Little trinkets!
This umbrella is pretty.
It is.
Right?
How much is this?
How about...
Miss! Miss!
Come look at this!
Miss,
what would you like?
This puppet...
Does it resemble our Zhong Kui painting?
Father hung a Zhong Kui painting at home,
to catch ghosts and ward off evil.
Excuse me, I'll take this.
Miss, you have great taste.
This was blessed at the temple.
It wards off evil and keeps you safe!
Dad!
I bought you something good.
What is it?
Come with me and you'll see.
Dad, listen to this.
The gold stolen from the gold shop...
...has all been recovered.
Now I've bought this Zhong Kui...
...to guard your door and keep you safe.
You won't have to fear the dead concubines
...coming to haunt you anymore.
This mansion is haunted.
Keep your voice down.
Don't let them hear you.
Master!
Master! Master!
Madam!
Master! Madam!
Master!
Master! Master!
Dad!
I want to swap rooms with you.
There's a cat outside my room.
It's been making noise all night.
Mengzhu.
A cat bit you when you were little.
Why are you still so afraid of cats?
I don't care.
I want to swap rooms with you.
Dad!
Alright, alright, alright.
Alright.
Oh, you...